Python has an interesting philosophy, but Zen of Python, it's a list collection of 19 software
principles written in poem form that influenced the design of the Python programming language,
and kind of really captures, I feel like the essence of it. It was published on a Python mailing list
in June of 1999 by Tim Peters. As we learned yesterday, Python is 30 years old.
Python 3 is 11 years old, so it's going to be old enough to vote soon, right?
So a cute little Easter egg and Python, the Zen of Python is in the Python interpreter.
So you should all have your ripples open. Type import, space this, and press enter.
Where I'm going to talk through some of the first principles I recommend coming back and
looking at the rest later. So the Zen of Python starts with beautiful is better than ugly,
explicit, better than implicit, simple, better than complex, complex, better than complicated.
It's an important one, an important distinction, flat, better than nested,
sparse is better than dense, and readability counts. So these are really important Python ideas.
Simple is better than complex, generally, Python programmers prefer to be explicit and write simple,
understandable, and maintainable code. Instead of, you know, maybe doing some ego flexing and writing,
things that are unnecessarily complex, I'm sure. Sure, developers, we've all seen things that
didn't just didn't need to be that complicated. Readability counts, making your code easy to read,
avoiding single character variable names, calling your functions with named parameters,
where applicable, using good variable names. This is really, I feel like really ties in hand with
Pepe 8. We learned about Pepe 8 yesterday. How it's an important style guide for Python developers
because most good Python code should look pretty similar, and that really helps in terms of
readability. All the imports are going to be at the top. You know if something is named with
camel case, then it's likely to be a class. Your variables are all lower class and divided with underscores.
Have a few more fun Easter eggs to show you. So I'm going to start my ripple here.
Let's see where did my ripple go? Oh, no, it looks like my ripple crashed. So if this kind of happens
to you, if you see any, you know, weirdness, things aren't working as expecting or as expected,
just hit this trash can here and it'll blow that away. And let's try that again. Awesome.
Okay, so our next Easter egg, we can do from underscore underscore. Remember those double underscores
are also called dunder in Python. From underscore underscore feature underscore underscore
import braces. That's not happening. And one of my favorite Easter eggs, if you import anti-gravity
should see I from little KCD. Maybe one of my favorites. And it just says you're flying how
with Python. So you learned it, you know, last night everything is so simple. Hello world is just
print, hello world in Python three put parentheses around this. You know, there's dynamic typing,
there's white space, you know. So whole new world. So you ever need a little pick me up just
import anti-gravity.